Guide to the Thomas M. Disch Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- January 2000 Acquisition, 1964-1998; 11.71; (15 boxes)
  - Electronic Files, Series III
    Box 43 (electronic files): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "MDM 7", 1984; 1 floppy disk (Box 43)
      2000-ycal-0113-d-0001
    - "The Roswell Incident", 1998; 1 compact disc
      2000-ycal-0113-d-0002
  - Audiovisual Material, Series IV
    - "Science Fiction: Familiar, Strange and Possible," A collection of audiocassettes and filmstrips for teachers use in the classroom. Schloat Productions, Prentice-Hall Media, Inc.
      - Filmstrips
        Boxes 44 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        - 1. Where the Wierd Ideas Come From, 1977; 2 filmstrips (Box 44)
        - 2. Doomsdays and Dystopias, 1977; 2 filmstrips
        - 3. Constructing Utopia, 1977; 2 filmstrips
        - 4. Crash Helmets for Future Shock, 1977; 2 filmstrips
        - 5. The Secret Identity of Monsters, 1977; 2 filmstrips
        - 6. New Selves for Old, 1977; 2 filmstrips
      - Audiocassettes
        Boxes 45 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        - 1. Where the Weird Ideas Come From, 1977; 1 (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399098)
        - 1. Where the Weird Ideas Come From, 1977; 1; 00:22:34; The program runs approximately 11 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399106)
          This appears to be a duplicate.
        - 2. Doomsdays and Dystopias, 1977; 1; 00:21:57; The program runs 11 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399114)
        - 2. Doomsdays and Dystopias, 1977; 1; 00:21:51; The program runs approximately 11 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. There is static on the tape. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399122)
          This audiocassette appears to be a duplicate.
        - 3. Constructing Utopia, 1977; 1; 00:20:44; The program runs about 10 1/2 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399130)
        - 3. Constructing Utopia, 1977; 1; 00:20:46; The program runs 10 1/2 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399148)
        - 4. Crash Helmets for Future Shock, 1977; 1; 00:23:40; The program runs about 12 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399155)
        - 4. Crash Helmets for Future Shock, 1977; 1; 00:23:19; The program runs a little more than 11 1/2 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399163)
        - 5. The Secret Identity of Monsters, 1977; 1; 00:23:52; The program runs close to 12 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399171)
        - 5. The Secret Identity of Monsters, 1977; 1; 00:23:48; The program runs close to 12 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399189)
        - 6. New Selves for Old, 1977; 1; 00:17:44; The program runs about 9 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399197)
        - 6. New Selves for Old, 1977; 1; 00:17:32; The program runs about 9 minutes and repeats. The first version contains tone to match audio with projector slides. (Box 45, Item barcode 39002091399205)
      - Program Guides and container, 1977 (Box 46 (Oversize))
- September 2006 Acquisition, 1908-2007; 52; (66 boxes) + 1 art
  - Juvenilia, 1955-1964, undated; 6 (Box 47)
  - Photographs, undated
  - Poems, writings and stories, undated; 2
  - Writings, undated; 2
  - NYU writings, 1963-1964
  - Poems, undated
  - College writings, 1962-1965
  - Rejections, 1963
  - Early diary, 1950s-1960s
  - First vain longings toward a novel, circa 1960
  - Neighbors
    - Typescript, undated; 5 (Box 48)
    - Early manuscripts, undated; 3
    - Manuscript, undated; 3
    - Typescript, undated; 6
    - Typescript, undated; 4 (Box 49)
    - Publication papers, 1977-1984
  - Dangerous Fictions: Generic Play in the Novels of Thomas M. Disch, Thesis by Elliot J. Atkins, University of Liverpool, 2001
  - The Dreams Our Stuff Is Made Of
    - Typescripts, notes and related materials, 1986-1997, undated; 8
    - Typescripts, undated; 6 (Box 50)
  - "Troll", 1982
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1980-1985; 2
  - Notebooks, undated; 9
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1976-1982
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1989-2005, undated; 10 (Box 51)
  - About the size of it, undated
  - BLT Russia, 1994
  - Children's garden of grammar, 1997
  - Hansen: FBI Spy, clippings, 2001
  - "Getting into death", 1988
  - "Kid Lit," typescripts, undated
  - "Stories: hard work", undated
  - "Stray Bullets," typescript, undated
  - Sequels, undated
  - Teacup, 1986, undated
  - "Turkeys," typescripts edited by Thomas Disch
  - Haiku, 2004, undated
  - "Missing Hours," television script by Thomas Disch for Miami Vice, 1987
  - On S.F., 1981-1985
  - "Santa Claus Explains," typescript, undated
  - "The Substitute", 1988-1999
  - "The Vampires," typescript, 1989
  - Poems, 2001, undated; 2
  - S.F. essays, undated
  - "Thomas M. Disch, 1940- My life as a child: a mini autobiography" from Something about the author series v.15, 1991
  - Theater, 1987-1991
  - Magazine rejections, 1988-1997
  - Ross Neher, undated
  - Contracts, 1981-1995 (Box 52)
  - Reviews, 1997-1999; 2
  - Neighbor's reviews, 1981; 3
  - Locus Award, 1999
  - Calendars, 2000, 2004
  - BLT 1986, 1982-1987
  - Ben Hur, 1989
  - Poetry mail, 1992-1997; 2
  - Inquiries, 1995-1998
  - Miscellaneous writings, undated; 4
  - Naylor novel
    - Drafts and notes, undated; 2
    - Drafts and notes, undated; 16 (Box 53)
    - Drafts and notes, undated; 4 (Box 54)
  - C.V. Clippings and ephemera, 1992-1998
  - Photographs, 1992-1997; 3
  - Disch ancestors, photograph, circa 1900
  - Disch photograph, undated
  - Nea Typannei, typescripts, undated
  - Music and personal, 1968-1992
  - Clippings, 1967-1968
  - How to know what you like, undated
  - The Pressure of Time
    - Drafts, undated; 9
  - Card files in boxes with details of prose and verse writings, dates of composition, submission and publication, 1960-1975 (Box 55)
  - Card files in boxes with details of prose and verse writings, dates of composition, submission and publication, 1960-1975 (Box 56)
  - Recordings of radio interviews, with accompanying papers, 1980-1988 (Box 57)
    Includes: "In Different voices: T.S. Elliot at 100 -- Symphony Space," "Letter from New York," "Strieber tape," "Public Affairs #16," "Aenouera [J. H.]"
  - Slides of paintings, 6 slides
  - The sub: A study in witchcraft, undated; 3
  - Books and theatre, 2004; 2
  - Books, reviews, theatre, undated; 2
  - "Tom's divine comedy: a vision", undated; 2
  - Reviews, undated; 3
  - Bibliography, 1995
  - "The coming civil war", 1998
  - Miscelaneous papers, 1999
  - Writings, undated; 6 (Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous writings, undated; 4
  - Notebooks, 1975, undated; 9
  - Poem to Lee Harwood, 1967-1968
  - Calendar/datebook, 1978-1981; 3
  - Correspondence, 1988-1991
  - Writings, related papers, 1979-1988; 2 (Box 59)
  - Calendars, datebooks, 1977-1987; 4
  - Diary, 1963
  - Notebooks, 1983-1985, undated; 16
  - Notebooks, 1981-1985; 9 (Box 60)
  - Financial papers, 1971
  - Writings and related papers, 1979; 2
  - "A masked ball, or Venice preserved," typescript and proposal for novel, undated; 2
  - "From collected reviews of Thomas M. Disch", undated
  - A Troll of Surewould Forest
    - Typescripts, undated; 2
    - Cover art transparencies, undated
  - "Praise for Thomas M. Disch," publicity, undated
  - Photographs of ads for "The Sub", undated
  - "The moon on the crest of the new fallen snow", undated
  - "The pressure of time" (outline, prologue, book one, two), undated; 3
  - Materials related to "Castle of indolence", 1996
  - Related to (sales) - "Tale of Dan de Lion", 1994
  - Materials, correspondence, re: "Burn this", 1984
  - Related to "McGonogall", 1997
  - "Xmas", 1969
  - Drafts, undated
  - Hummingbird, Matthew, correspondence, 1989-1991
  - Materials re: "Yes, let's", 1990
  - Miscellanous papers, undated (Box 61)
  - 92nd st Y workshop, 1999-2000
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1964
  - "The golden trough, children's stories", 1996; 2
  - Materials in box labeled "On S.F. originals/Mecca", 1987-1995; 4
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated; 3
  - Correspondence, 1981-1994; 6
  - Correspondence, 1995-1997, undated; 6 (Box 62)
  - "Frankenstein libretto", undated
  - Material in folder "WNYC 2000", 1999-2001
  - Collected materials on "pedophile priests", 2001-2002
  - Miscellaneous, 1986-1992; 3
  - Notebook, circa 1992
  - "Apocalypse NYC/Mortician", 1993
  - Materials related to "Ben Hur", 1990
  - Disch on S. F., undated; 2
  - Correspondence related to Ruth Lilly poetry prize, 2002
  - Lind, M., correspondence, 2000-2001; 2
  - Dick, Anne R., correspondence, 2002
  - Correspondence, 2002-2004
  - Correspondence, 2002-2004; 4 (Box 63)
  - Correspondence, 1951-2005; 9
  - Financial records, 1989-2005; 4
  - Correspondence, 1979-2002; 27 (Box 64)
  - Photographs and slides, 1971-1980; 9 slides
  - Disch family photograph with inscription on the back, 1908
  - Unidentified photograph, undated
  - Chocolate containers, undated
  - Journals, 1986; 2
  - "Teaching clips", 1996
  - "Just friends: a magazine", undated
  - Magazines, 1962-1976 (Box 65)
  - "The village alien writings on S.F.", undated
  - "The new dark ages," typescript, undated
  - "Doomsday ideas", undated
  - "Anti- privacy", undated
  - Publishing materials, 1992-1999
  - Correspondence (publishers, etc.), 1985-1995
  - "APA", 1990
  - "Collected reviews", 2000
  - "Rejections books/mags", 1993-2004
  - "Seedlings aborted foetuses", 1985-1992
  - "New dark ages", 1992-2001
  - "Essays/intros", 2002, undated
  - "Ideas", 1990-2001
  - Play ideas, undated
  - "Castle of perseverance", undated
  - Russians (Russian correspondence), 1991
  - "Rusher businessman options", 1995-1998
  - "Barney's BLT silence king of Kalahari", 1998
  - Carroll and Graf publishers, 1988-1994
  - "All the shabby mandarins", undated
  - "Brave little toaster", 1985-1995
  - "The businessman", 1981-1993
  - "Sweden/Replick", 1995
  - Correspondence with Virginia Kidd, 1995-1996
  - "The masked ball or Venice Preserved", undated
  - "Borderline: proposal for a novel", undated
  - "Hell's bells: poetry and madness" (a book proposal), undated
  - "Christians in Texas", circa 2005
  - "The matter of 9/11" (clippings correspondence, poems), 2001
  - "Movies," Shapiro correspondence, 1976-1988 (Box 66)
  - Reviews, undated
  - "Photos from Elgort", 1979, undated
  - Manuscript drafts/notes: "The naming of the birds," "The Teddy Bear's tragedy," "The happy turnip", undated
  - "About the size of it", undated
  - "Auschwitz: a comedy", circa 1964
  - "Art list", 2005
  - Correspondence, 1963-2005; 2
  - Journals, 1963-1977, undated; 3
  - Poetry reviews, 1983-1996
  - "Poetry chronological list", undated
  - "Yes, Let's", 1989-1993
  - Note, undated
  - Newspapers, 1988-2002
  - "NYC Opera Vox 2003 Showcasing American Composers," production programs
  - Brochures, 2002
  - Address book/journals, 1986, undated; 2
  - "The vampires", 1998
  - "NYU Library", 1965-1975
  - Writings, 1975-2005, undated; 3 (Box 67)
  - "Voices of the kill" (short stories), undated; 2
  - Theatre reviews for The Nation April 1987-March 1991 by Thomas Disch, clippings (photocopies), 1987-1991; 2
  - Modern Haiku, etc., 2004
  - "The castle of perseverance", 2003
  - Bibliography, undated
  - "Doug Holt's genealogies", 1986-1989
  - "Davis, Matt,--'03 taxes", 2001-2003
  - "On wings of song", 2003, undated
  - "The Atheist: an Oriental tale", undated
  - New manuscripts, 2001, undated
  - "The Teddy Bear's tragedy", undated
  - "Poetry essays", 2001-2007
  - "Reviews", 1986, undated
  - "Divine C. detritus", 2000, undated; 2
  - Correspondence and photos, 2004
  - Diary, 1957-1959
  - Writings, undated; 2 (Box 68)
  - Mecca, undated; 2
  - Miscellaneous papers, 2001-2002
  - "Me" (Materials/clippings on Disch), 1983-1986
  - "Me-more", 1986-1997
  - Materials re: fire/moving, 1999-2002
  - "Submissions history", 1993-1995
  - Manuscripts, undated
  - "Exercise class", 1972, undated; 2
  - "Maelstrom", 1977-1981
  - "Wonderlands", 1984
  - "Sex and violence", undated
  - University of Minnesota, 1973-1981
  - Prentice Hall, 1975-1982
  - Taxes, 1972-1991; 15 (Box 69)
  - Keogh IRA, 1984-1992; 2
  - Newspapers, 1981-1984; 3
  - Newspapers, 1983-1994; 6 (Box 70)
  - Theology Today, 1993-1994; 5
  - Charles Scribner's & Sons, fall and winter, 1980-1981
  - Entertainment Weekly, 1991 June-1991 July
  - The New Leader, 1997
  - The Weekly Standard, 2001-2003; 3
  - The Weekly Standard, 2003-2005; 4 (Box 71)
  - Articles, interview, re: Disch, 2001, undated
  - Omni 2 copies, 1987 September
  - Newsweek, 1988
  - Publishers Weekly, 1991-1992
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1975, undated
  - Printed material, 1987-1994; 4
  - Newspapers, 1977-1988; 2
  - "Depraved independence", 2001-2002 (Box 72)
  - "Echo round his bones", 1991
  - "Genocides", 1987-1989, undated
  - Reviews, 1971-1976
  - "102 H-bombs", undated
  - On wings of song, undated
  - Death of Broadway book, 1991-1992
  - "Amnesia," screenplay, undated
  - Taxes, 1976-1989; 2
  - Transcript, high school (photocopy), undated
  - "Ben Hur", 1989-1991
  - Poetry contracts, 1971-1984
  - "Bibliobulemia", 1987
  - Anthologies/contracts, 1963-1999; 3
  - "Bad moon rising", undated
  - "Jekyl and Hyde 70", 1970
  - Tie-in contracts, 1971-1977
  - Movie tie-ins, 1977-1979
  - Blank disk labels, notes, undated
  - "Teddy Bears in Hell/ Watt/London", 1985
    Papers related to the development of an "interactive software program" for an anthology of interactive short stories based on fictional work. Includes prospectus, agreement, disks and notes.
  - Ben-Hur notebook, undated (Box 73)
  - Financial papers, 1973-1998; 3
  - Receipts, 1979-1998; 4
  - Bank statements, 1990-1998; 3
  - Income tax papers, 1993-1997; 6
  - Grants-fix, 1987
  - Calendars, 1988-1997; 2
  - Composition books, undated; 2 (Box 74)
  - Notebooks, undated; 13
  - Miscellaneous, 1995, undated
  - Newspaper clippings, 1991-1995
  - "Black Rooster Three," "Writer's voice of the West Side YMCA", 1976, 1995
  - The M. D.
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1998, undated
    - Manuscripts, theater reviews, undated; 3
    - Manuscripts, theater reviews, undated; 2 (Box 75)
  - Autographs, undated
  - Theatre reviews, undated; 2
  - Turkey notes and receipts, undated
  - Grid stories, notes, undated
  - Black on black, undated
  - Jason, 1970
  - "Ziesing", undated
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1995, undated; 2
  - Muellenhof, 1995-1996
  - Financial business papers, 1982-1997
  - Reviews, 1996-1998
  - "Ben Hur", circa 1987
  - "Miami Vice", 1987
  - "Gays in uniform", 1993, undated
  - "Brave little toaster", 1979-1981
  - News, reviews, 1993-1994; 3
  - "Killer at the con", 1980
  - "The House of Morden", undated
  - "The freedom year", 1980, undated
  - "Snake in the manger," "Dark verses," "Light", 1990-1991
  - Duty and responsibility, 1984
  - Uncollected and leftovers, undated
  - Incomplete or abandoned, 1968
  - 334 East, 11th Str., 1967
  - Miscellaneous papers, undated
  - Computer manuals, 1983-1984; 4 (Box 76)
  - Ellis papers, 1980-1998; 2
  - Copyright forms, 1971-1992
  - UCLA/Ellison, 1975
  - Clarion, 1974-1983
  - Lectures, speech, 1974-1991; 3
  - Johns Hopkins, 1989-1991
  - "Camp concentration", 1993-1994
  - Clara, 1970-1982; 2
  - Slide/Schloat, 1993 (Box 77)
  - Wesleyan University, 1975-1988
  - "Pressure", 1971-1981
  - "334", undated; 2
  - Usher, 1975-1976
  - "Frankenstein", 1981-1982
  - Mohrbooks, 1979-1992
  - "A temporary licence", undated
  - Publishing/financial papers, 1972-1990
  - New reviews, 1984-1992
  - Clippings, papers, 1990-1992; 3
  - "Affirmations", undated
  - Letters, rejections, 1983-1991
  - "Strangeness", 1975-1980
  - Farmer, P. J., 1970-1988
  - Correspondence and financial papers, 1976-1991; 3 (Box 78)
  - Foreign rights, 1971-1992
  - Poetry typescripts, undated; 2
  - Financial papers, 1987-1992
  - "Camp concentration," contract, royalties, 1967-1992
  - "Black Alice," contracts, royalties, 1969-1990
  - Fundamental Disch, 1980, undated
  - Kaypro utilities doc., undated
  - "Europe the lost continent", 1978, undated
  - "Black Lotus", 1991
  - On Wings of Song, correspondence, 1977-1990
  - "Fun with your new head", 1968-1974
  - "Genocides," contract, royalties, 1973-1984
  - "White fang," contracts, royalties, 1965-1982
  - "House fear guilt," contracts, 1966-1975
  - "Echo," contracts, royalties, 1967-1983
  - Changing agents, 1994-1995
  - "The pressure of time", undated
  - "My life as a child", 1992-1993
  - Printed material, 1989-1990 (Box 79)
  - Clippings, 1982-1994; 2
  - Opera, 1997-1998
  - "Microcosmic tales", undated
  - "Cardinal detoxes audition at RAPP", 1990
  - Journal, undated
  - Notebook, undated; 6
  - "Priest," reviews, 1995
  - Computer manual, 1985
  - Playscripts by Patricia Dizenzo
    - "The new leader", undated
    - "The island", undated
  - Playscripts by Charles Dizenzo
    - "The geraniums", undated
    - "The draper cone", undated
    - "Nero", undated
    - "The counselor takes a plunge", undated
  - Poetry typescripts, undated; 2
  - Miscellaneous, 1997-2000 (Box 80)
  - "Ben Hur", undated; 2
  - "Voices of the Kill", undated; 2
  - Reviews and public relations files, 1984-1990, undated; 3
  - Copies of short stories, 2001
  - Diary, 1992-1995
  - Theatre reviews, (photocopies), 1987-1991
  - Old business contracts, royalties, etc., 1982-2004, undated; 8
  - Old business contracts, royalties, etc., 1998, undated; 3 (Box 81)
  - Taxes, 1998-2002; 4
  - Charles Naylor journal, undated; 7
  - "NAYLOR papers", 2005; 2
  - "Troll," and other stories by Tom Disch which appeared in Amazing Stories, 1992 (Box 82)
  - "Alexander, Jane/Wellstone", undated
  - Charles Naylor most important papers, 1967-2005
  - Notebook
  - Naylor letters from book publishers, 2005
  - Jerry Buchanan show poster, 1975
  - Naylor correspondence with Gloria Salimando, 1964
  - Notebook with drafts, 2006
  - Naylor record of 1999 fire losses
  - Charles Naylor passport documentation, 1969-1978
  - Magazine and letter to Disch in Whole Foods Bay, 2006
  - "Happy 50th brithday to Dana", 2000
  - Miscellaneous, 2006
  - Correspondence, 1968, 2006
  - "Disch celebrity love (about the size of it) orig.", undated; 5
  - "New dark ages", undated
  - "New dark ages", undated; 3 (Box 83)
  - Correspondence, 1989
  - Musical scores, 1976, undated
  - Address books, undated
  - Photographs, undated; 4
  - Photographs, 1980-2003; 22
  - "Bro[?] Jerry and friend," photograph, undated
  - "Iverson, Diane, Alan's sister in 1956," photograph
  - "Summer 1960 trip to Boston/Salem" (Box 84)
  - "Trip to Istanbul," photographs, 1967-1968; 3
  - "Rome," photographs and notebook, 1970, undated; 2
  - "Venice, Sophia, personal/spoiled," photographs, undated
  - "Voyage to Naples, Pompeii," photographs, undated
  - "Travel photographs", undated
  - "Dad's visit to Holy," photographs, undated
  - "Westbrookville '83," photographs, [1983]
  - "Sheridan Sq., Greg Sandon," photographs, undated
  - "Bermuda," photographs, 1992
  - "Readercon," photographs and negatives, 1992
  - "London, our sublet of the Sutherland House, Marilyn H. and M[?] Ponsot," photographs and negatives, undated
  - "London," photographs and negatives, 1968
  - "Toys which would all be destroyed in the fire of 2001," photographs and 15 color 8mm negatives, 1986 June
  - "Tom Disch," photograph, undated
  - "Winter River with Jane, MOMA/from Soroyan," negatives and contact sheet, undated
  - "Trip in the snow, Milford," photographs and negatives, undated
  - "Visit to Minn," photographs and negatives, 1971
  - "Lee [Harwood] on a visit to NYC," photographs and negatives, undated
  - Photographs and negatives, undated; 5
  - "Central Park," circa 57 uncut 35 millimeter black and white negatives in 2 boxes, 1960 May
  - Circa 100 uncut 35 millimeter black and white negatives in 2 canisters, 1 empty canister, undated
  - 35 millimeter black and white, and color negatives, undated; 4
  - Tom Disch, 2 8"x10" black and white negatives, undated
  - "Disch photos," 105 color 8 millimeter negatives on 7 discs, undated; 7 (Box 85)
  - "Metlife", 1960; 39 slides
  - "On the ship from Istanbul," includes note fragment, 1968; 28 slides
  - "Sprocks slides", undated; 2 slides
  - "Summer of '65, Germany/Austria,", 1965-1966; 9 slides
  - "Paintings," includes notes, circa 1980; 23 slides
  - Escala [T]ors, undated; 6 slides
  - Maps and brochures, 1955-1981; 6
  - UK maps and brochures, 1969-1984; 2
  - Europe maps and brochures, 1973-1985; 3
  - "Ben Hur," stage production program, 1988
  - RAPP theatre brochure, Fall 1989
  - Small objects, undated (Box 86)
  - Small objects, doll furniture, small painting, eggs, etc., undated (Box 87)
  - Stage production programs, 1991-1997; 10 (Box 88)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, award, 1999 May 19
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters Ceremonial program, 3 copies, 1999 May 19
  - Newspapers, 1986-1996; 4
  - Newspapers, 1977-2002; 13 (Box 89)
  - American Heritage 3 copies, 1999
  - Camera Arts 3 copies, 1981; 2
  - Chronicles, 1989-1994; 2
  - Entertainment Weekly, 1990-1995; 7 (Box 90)
  - GQ, 1971; 2
  - GQ Scene, 1967
  - Harpers, 1973-1982
  - High Times, 1980-1982; 3
  - Inquiry, 1982-1985; 2
  - Interzone, 1988-1998; 2
  - Jump, 1995-1996 (Box 91)
  - Light, 1994-1996
  - Moorcock@60.com, 1999
  - Mpls. St. Paul, 1984-1986; 2
  - The New Leader, 1997
  - The Nation, 1986-1992; 13
  - The Nation, 1992-1995; 3 (Box 92)
  - Omni, 1980-1989; 7
  - Poetry Since Tuesday, undated
  - Skeptic 3 copies, 1998
  - "Thomas M. Disch: A candid talk with the Hugo winning author," Locus, 2001 June
  - Time, Newsweek, 1973-1984
  - Twilight Zone, 1982
  - Twilight Zone, 1983-1985; 6 (Box 93)
  - The Weekly Standard, 2002-2003; 2
  - Sci Fi magazines, 1968-1986
  - Magazines, 1973-2005; 9
  - American Book Review, 1992 (Box 94 (Oversize))
  - The Boston Review, 1997-1998
  - The Daily Press, 1996
  - "Disch Fulfilled," article from Entertainment section of The Star Tribune, 1999
  - The Los Angeles Times Book Review, 1992-2001
  - Newsday, 1982
  - The New York Press, 1997; 4 (Box 95 (Oversize))
  - The New York Press, 1997-2001; 4 (Box 96 (Oversize))
  - The New York Press, 2001-2002 (Box 97 (Oversize))
  - The New York Sun, 2003; 4
  - The New York Sun, 2003-2004; 4 (Box 98 (Oversize))
  - The New York Sun, 2004; 2 (Box 99 (Oversize))
  - The New York Times, 1998
  - The New York Times Book Review, 1975-1998; 2
  - The New York Times Book Review, 1998 (Box 100 (Oversize))
  - The Philadelphia Inquirer, 1983 December 25
  - The Star Weekly, 1964
  - The Times Literary Supplement, 1978-2003; 2
  - The Voice, 1980-1982; 4 (Box 101 (Oversize))
  - The Voice, 1982 (Box 102 (Oversize))
  - The Washington Post Book World, 1982-1997; 3
  - Ad material, 1964 (Box 103 (Oversize))
  - Broadsides, 1976-1985